[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[crowd cheering]
Sir. one minute warning.
Congratulations again.
Heard anything from
Betty. from my daughter?
No. sir. We tried
her several times.
Okay.
Thank you.
[male announcer] All right. New
Hampshire. we are moments away.
Are you ready?
[crowd] Ready for Ross! Ready for
Ross! Ready for Ross! Ready for Ross!
Ready for Ross! Ready for Ross!
[male announcer]
Ladies and gentlemen.
the next President of the
United States of America.
Thaddeus Ross!
[crowd applauds. cheers]
Thank you.
Tonight. America has spoken
in one of the most important
elections of our lifetimes.
We've recognized the
urgency of this moment.
From the disappearance
of half of mankind
to the emergence
of a celestial mass
in the Indian Ocean.
the threats we face show
no signs of slowing down.
But the only way we can
overcome them is together!
Tonight. President Ross
embraced the theme of togetherness
in his acceptance speech.
but his past tells
a different story.
especially when it comes to working
with heroes like Captain America.
As two of our nation's
most important leaders.
some question if they can overcome
their at-times tumultuous history
to face the challenges ahead.
- [bartender] Here you go. Cap.
- [female reporter] During his time as a...
Put your money away.
It's on the house.
[Sam chuckles]
Thanks. Charlie.
[female reporter]
...leading to Ross
being branded with the
moniker of "the Hulk Hunter."
Following Hulk and the
Abomination's destruction of Harlem.
Ross was criticized
for what some called
"an unwarranted outburst"
during a press conference.
In fact. many blamed Ross
for the collateral damage.
believing it was his relentless pursuit
of Banner's Hulk that led to the rampage.
It also resulted in the President-elect's
estrangement from his daughter.
Doctor Betty Ross. Bruce
Banner's ex-girlfriend.
But in a surprising turn of events.
he managed to shift the narrative.
and silence his harshest critics
by apprehending the man
responsible for the Abomination.
[alarm blares]
[electrical buzzing]
[jet engine roaring]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
How we lookin' down there?
Well. SERPENT mercenaries entered
with a package about an hour ago.
They're handing it to
the buyer any minute.
We know what they're carrying?
That is classified
per the White House.
[sighs] Of course it is.
Where's Eagle-One? We
have strike authorization.
Eagle-One is entering
the target airspace now.
[jet engine roars]
Upload the compound's
covert entry points.
Covert? Really? You must be new.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
Wait for it.
Sam. SEAL team is
six minutes out.
[Captain America] Copy that.
How the hell did
he just do that?
Cap's gear was a gift from the
Wakandans for helping them out.
I heard even the wrapping
paper was made of vibranium.
No. man. I'm kidding. Come on.
Joaquin. Redwing's pickin'
up hostages inside.
- I'm goin' in.
- Negative.
The package is the priority.
[Captain America] Have the
SEALs track down the package.
I'm on the hostages.
Redwing. send them a
scan of the building.
[speaks Spanish]
What is it?
That's Sidewinder. He's
the head of SERPENT.
He's not supposed to be here.
[hostages whimpering]
[priest praying in Spanish]
Ah.
You're praying. Padre.
[in Spanish] The buyer
told me to meet him here.
I'm not leaving until I
get the money owed to me.
- Padre.
- [groans]
[priest praying in Spanish]
Padre. Padre. Padre. Padre.
[sighs]
We did not come all this way
to hear rosaries. Father.
Where is the buyer?
I don't know.
- I don't know.
- No. I don't know... No. I don't know...
[in English] Kill them.
- [hostage man] No. No!
- Kill them one at a time.
[speaks Spanish]
Silencio!
[male mercenary on radio] Captain
America is here. Do you copy?
Move. move. move!
Vámonos. vámonos.
Get the package outta here.
[♪ tense music playing]
SERPENT's on the move
with the canister. Sam.
[Captain America] I'm
kinda busy right now!
[grunting]
Redwing. on my mark.
[female mercenary] Stop.
Stay back! Or we'll shoot them.
[in Spanish] Don't worry.
You have been very brave.
Thank you. Captain
America. Thank you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
SERPENT's gettin' farther
away with the canister. Sam.
and Sidewinder's
headed to the chapel.
I already know what
you're trying to do.
You can't be at
two places at once.
All right. this time.
- But don't get yourself killed.
- No dying. Copy that.
Buyer didn't show. Looks
like you need better clients.
You don't need to worry.
I'll find whoever
wasted my time.
You have bigger concerns.
- [yells]
- [Captain America grunts]
[both straining]
[blows landing]
[Captain America grunting]
[groans. chuckles]
The Captain America I dreamt
of killing was bigger than you.
I'm happy to disappoint.
[sighs]
I bet you break easy.
Not that easy.
Not that hard.
I heard your rib go.
You need a minute?
[pained] Nope. Nope.
let's get this over with.
I got shit to do today.
Whoo-hoo!
Damn.
Nobody saw that.
Sam. package is secured.
[both shout]
I'll add your star
to my collection.
[bone cracking]
Need a minute?
[groaning]
That's what I thought.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
Save some for us. Cap.
He has a fractured
arm. so be gentle.
[chuckles]
[Ross] "Keep your face
always to the sunshine.
and the shadows will
fall behind you."
The quote was Betty's idea.
She's still not
speaking with you?
No.
She doesn't believe
I've changed.
Really changed.
I don't think I'm
gonna get another shot.
Comin' up on the end of my
first hundred days. Leila.
They're gonna define me.
This treaty's gotta work.
[phone vibrates]
Hello.
[major] Mr. President.
the mission was a success.
All right. fill me in.
[major] Cap and the SEAL
team saved the hostages.
The package is secure
and en route to the US.
- [Captain America] How's your brother?
- Oh. wow. you remembered.
- He's in the Air Force.
- Yeah.
- Probably 'cause of you.
- [Captain America laughs]
I try not to hold
that against him.
- It's a weird place for a handoff. right?
- Mm-hmm.
Wide open. soft perimeter.
You think the buyer ever
intended on showin' up?
You think SERPENT got played?
What are they sayin'?
Same thing. Contract
was anonymous.
Fifty mil to steal the
canister en route to Japan.
Then show up here
and meet the buyer.
[Captain America] Hmm.
Let us know if you get
a trace on Sidewinder.
- Good work.
- Thank you.
You'll notice. I did not die.
and people are saying
I did not die in style.
Who is saying that?
- People.
- What people?
- Everybody. Everybody is saying that.
- [chuckles]
Look. tell me I don't make
your old gear look brand-new.
You've got on the
greaves upside down.
I'm joking.
You look good. man.
All right. Fair enough.
That means that you're finally
gonna introduce me to Ant-Man?
Nope.
Well. at least you gotta teach
me your aerial kick. man.
Look. if I'm gonna be Falcon.
I gotta know everything.
In no way are you
ready for that.
But I got a guy who'll
teach you the fundamentals
from the ground up.
Absolutely.
Now. he's not a people person.
So you gotta learn how
to keep your mouth shut.
Can you do that?
[Captain America sighs]
He's gonna love me.
bro! Are you kidding me?
- That's not the right answer.
- He's gonna love me.
[♪ "Ante Up" playing]
[song fades]
What's up. OG?
Who's the pretty boy?
"Pretty boy"? You didn't
tell gramps about me?
I'm the new Falcon.
- No. you're not.
- Yes. I am.
This is Joaquin Torres.
Been workin' with
him for three years.
I haven't figured out
how to shut him up yet.
So what are we doing
here? Orthopedics? Uh...
How to relearn how to walk
after you break a hip?
Oh. sh...
Oh. shit.
[Sam] That's Isaiah Bradley.
The... The Isaiah Bradley?
You brought me to the forgotten
Cap? Why didn't you say something?
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Your missions in
Korea are legendary.
And what. and after that. no action?
I mean. a lot's changed in the world.
We could've used
another super soldier.
The United States government
threw me in prison for 30 years.
They experimented
on me for decades.
Yikes. that's... that sucks.
Can we start?
Let's do it.
No vibranium wings.
no shield. no super
soldier serum.
I wanna see if he's
got three in him.
[Joaquin] Get those flags. Sam!
[♪ "Elephant" playing]
Cap v Cap!
[exclaims]
[Joaquin whoops]
- [Sam] That's one.
- [Joaquin claps]
Let's go!
[Joaquin exclaims] Orthopedic.
That's two.
[laughs]
I'm sorry. What were you sayin'?
See? Not a people person.
- In a fight. the last hit...
- Is the only hit that matters.
I know. Shut up. but thanks.
All right. that's it.
Tag me in. I'm ready.
Captain America doesn't
get to take five. Let's go.
I need to take this.
I'm not takin' five.
- You still got the plastic on.
- No! I don't...
Maybe I wanted it on there.
Oh. you want me to make the
text bigger? So you can read it?
Yeah. I'll hold
for the President.
Where you going?
You wanna talk about it?
It just doesn't
sit right with me.
Captain America. answering
to the President.
The President of the
country who stole your life?
It's not just that.
We're talkin' about
Thaddeus "Thunderbolt" Ross.
Son of a bitch earned
that nickname. too.
Look. I know. Isaiah. firsthand.
Remember. Ross threw
me in the Raft.
Hounded me. Steve and
Natasha for years.
So why are you workin' for him?
[sighs]
As long as you do.
Captain America stands
for people like him.
You've got no business
workin' for the government.
You see what's
going on out there?
The country is lost.
Standing next to the
President. even if it's Ross...
it gives people hope.
Now. come on. give
me some credit.
I have a friend who
works in the White House.
She'll let me know if Ross
starts acting out of turn.
None of this means
I forgot about you.
I see what you're doin'.
What?
Pullin' that counseling
bullshit on me.
[laughs]
Look. trust me.
My eyes are wide
open on this. okay?
I know Ross will never change.
but he is the President.
So you gonna tell me what he wanted or
are you plannin' on makin' me guess?
He invited Joaquin and
I to the White House.
and I said under one condition.
If he extended an
invitation to you as well.
I know you're gonna say no.
but it would mean a lot
to me if you were there.
We just...
gotta get you a suit.
I have a damn suit.
For real?
Then why are you always wearin'
that ratty-ass sweatsuit?
[laughs]
Come on. you gonna come or what?
[♪ hip-hop playing.
Blackway "Get It Done"]
[Sam] See. Isaiah? This
is what I'm talking about.
Now you're going to the
White House. Look at that.
- You look good. OG.
- [Joaquin] Wow. man. Damn.
I told you I was gonna get
you out of those sweats.
Look at you now. man.
Yeah. I didn't know Men's
Warehouse made that size.
[laughs]
Hey. Faith and I
got married in this.
- Okay. all right. all right.
- [Isaiah chuckles]
I'm sure she would be proud.
I hope so.
Feels strange to walk right
into the belly of the beast.
- Hey. I'm sure it can't be easy.
- [Isaiah] It ain't.
Which is why we gotta celebrate. I
don't care if it is Ross in charge.
We are guests of honor
at the White House. man!
- When does that ever happen?
- [Sam] Right.
And they sent us a limo. man.
What?
And we look good.
- [Joaquin] Yeah.
- [Sam] What?
Old school. you got
your smell-good on.
- What?
- [Joaquin laughs]
And you got the houndstooth on.
And we got the good stuff.
It's party time. [laughs]
[♪ song continues]
[photographer 1]
Captain America!
[photographer 2] Captain.
Captain. over here.
- Cap. over here!
- [photographer 3] Mr. Bradley.
[photographer 2] Over here!
- Hey. Isaiah. Check it out.
- Oh.
[photographers clamoring]
Whoa. man. look at this!
Oh. we gotta get a pic.
Let's do it.
Tres amigos on three.
Uno. dos. tres. Ah!
[chuckles]
[Joaquin] Yeah. that's my
new wallpaper. Look at that.
- [Isaiah] Pretty good.
- It's good?
- [Isaiah] Can you send it to me?
- Yeah. I'll AirDrop it to you right now.
You do know what
AirDrop is. right?
Of course. I know
what AirDrop is.
- What's AirDrop?
- [laughs]
You see. you should have it.
Just hit "Accept" and it pops up.
- [Isaiah] I did that.
- Excuse me. gentlemen.
The President needs Mr. Wilson.
I'll see you guys inside.
- Hey.
Sam. just keep an open mind.
Why? What am I walking into?
Thi... This is not
the picture you took.
Oh. I sent you
the wrong picture.
- Oh. my Lord.
- [laughs]
[Ross] Well. that's
a very good point.
I'll consider it.
Wilson.
Folks. can you give us the room?
Uh...
[chuckles]
Thanks.
Doctor's orders.
Not quite a cigar. but
better than that damn gum.
[Sam] Hmm.
Thanks for comin' in.
Welcome to the White House.
Well. thank you for
the invite. sir.
I have to admit. I'm still
gettin' used to the new look.
[chuckles] Yeah. well.
they said lose the mustache
or lose the election.
Thanks for your
help down in Mexico.
Retrieving that canister might
just have saved this treaty.
I was just doing my job. sir.
You and I haven't always agreed
on how much latitude
enhanced individuals deserve.
But what you've accomplished has
given me reason to reconsider.
Which is why I want
you. Captain America.
to help me rebuild the Avengers.
- The Avengers?
- Yes. sir.
Well. with all due respect. sir.
when you passed the Sokovia Accords.
you tore the Avengers apart.
Why the change of heart?
I represent all Americans now.
Hell. half of 'em wouldn't even
be here without the Avengers.
The country needs this.
And when we disagree on how
to manage a situation...
what happens then?
We figure it out together.
Look. you don't have to
give me an answer now.
Just think about it.
Prime Minister Ozaki.
- Great to see you. sir.
- And you.
Thank you for being here.
Here we are.
Sam Wilson. Prime
Minister Ozaki.
[speaks Japanese]
Not bad. [chuckles]
- Would you like a picture?
- Sure.
Sam. please.
[photographer 4] Now.
stand a little bit closer.
- Thank you. gentlemen.
- Thank you.
- [speaks Japanese]
Work with me. Sam.
We'll show the world
a better way forward.
That was unexpected.
Maybe it's an opportunity.
So?
How was it?
He asked me to
restart the Avengers.
- Wait. what now?
- [chuckles]
- That's huge. man.
- I don't know.
We'd have to work for him.
[announcer] Ladies
and gentlemen.
the President of the United
States. Thaddeus Ross.
Good evening.
everyone. Good evening.
It's my great
privilege to host you
at the White House on
this historic evening.
When the celestial mass
emerged in the Indian Ocean.
we did what we often do.
We squabbled over it.
Countries rushed in to
claim it as their own.
setting up research facilities
to exploit its resources.
[♪ pensive music playing]
What was found
inside that island
is nothing short of the
discovery of the millennium.
Its potential applications
in tech. in medicine.
in defense are immeasurable.
It's even more indestructible
than vibranium.
And it's not controlled
by an isolationist nation.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I present to you...
adamantium.
The first and only
refined sample
was stolen from a
Japanese mining site.
But happily. it's been recovered
and is in a secure location.
And we have two incredibly
brave men to thank for that.
Joaquin Torres and our own
Captain America. Sam Wilson.
What we do next
with this discovery
will determine how
history judges us.
If we ratify this treaty.
together we can produce
enough adamantium
to fairly and equitably
distribute it around the world.
[♪ The Fleetwoods "Mr.
Blue" playing over speakers]
♪ I'm Mr. Blue Wa-oo-wa-oo ♪
Sir. you need to sit down.
[song stops]
- [guests clamoring]
- Isaiah! What are you doing?
- [guest screams]
- [grunts]
Sam!
- Sir. are you hit?
- No.
[agent] Go. go. go!
[gunshot]
[all speaking Japanese]
- [gunshots]
- [guests scream]
- [gunshot]
- [grunts]
Mr. President. come with me.
[both grunting]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Shit.
[horn honks]
Isaiah!
[siren blaring]
All team leaders.
eyes on! Eyes on!
- Get on the ground now!
- Do not move.
What's happening?
I don't know. But
you gotta stop.
- We got him right there!
- Move in. move in!
- [lead agent] Stop!
- [Sam] Don't!
I can't go back inside. Sam.
Run. and it'll be
worse than that.
Please. Isaiah.
Hey. take it easy!
Watch my suit.
Please. watch my suit.
[♪ tense music playing]
Cap. I can't let you in.
Hey!
Sam!
- Sir. you can't... you can't...
- [card scanner beeps]
Sir!
- [Leila] Sorry. Mr. President.
- Hey. hey. hey.
He stays.
Everybody else. out.
[Ross] Agent Taylor. you too.
Are you okay?
I should be asking
you that. sir.
Not my first time being shot at.
Look. I know how this
must look. but...
[door opens]
Can we have a minute?
She stays.
Meet Ruth Bat-Seraph.
my security advisor.
Sir. there's no way Isaiah
could have done this.
- Except he did.
- Maybe somebody got to him.
You're really defending a man
who just tried to kill
the President in front...
- We don't know what happened.
- Enough.
What do we know?
There were five shooters.
Isaiah was one of them.
As was Secret Service
and active military.
This was a coordinated
terrorist attack. sir.
[sighs]
What else do you have?
The song that preceded the shooting.
we think it was a cue for the attack.
Sir. Isaiah looked like
he wasn't in control.
He had no idea where he was.
So you're suggesting what?
[Sam] Let me investigate.
[scoffs]
Don't you think you're a
little too close to this?
Sir. your inner circle
has been compromised.
There's possibility
of another attack now.
And what exactly do
you have to offer
that our entire intelligence
and defense apparatus can't?
Well. I won't sit
around and let Isaiah...
Look. I know how important
Bradley is to you.
But consider the optics.
Captain America conducts
a personal investigation
of a friend who tried to
assassinate the President.
Isaiah sacrificed
everything for this country.
He's a soldier. A patriot.
He had no reason to do this.
He had every reason.
Bradley was in prison
for rescuing his own men.
experimented on for 30 years.
The things done to him are
enough to make anyone snap.
Sir. you invited me
here to work together.
- So let's work together.
- I'm afraid that offer expired
when your friend
tried to kill me.
[Ross sighs]
Sam. you shouldn't even
be in these situations.
You're not Steve Rogers.
Ruth.
you have my full authority
to put this thing to bed.
Before this treaty gets
compromised any further.
So that's it?
I'm done?
You're done.
This is bullshit.
and you know it.
This is politics.
So you better wise up. son.
"Son." Who you calling "son"?
Sam. What the hell
are you doing?
I'm going to clear Isaiah.
Storming in there
ain't gonna help him.
- You need Ross on your side.
- Ross?
Open your eyes.
I offer to help. and
he sends me packin'.
Ross is on his own side.
He always has been.
Either you can't see that.
or you don't want to.
Hey.
Don't be that guy.
And what guy is that?
The one who has to
do it the hard way.
Looks like I am that guy.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[reporter] The nation
remains on high alert.
The Justice Department has
signaled a death penalty case
will be pursued
against Isaiah Bradley.
Just five minutes. Cap.
I could be
court-martialed for this.
I appreciate it. Payumo.
Yes. sir.
[sighs]
[door clanks]
How you holdin' up?
Not so good. brother Sam.
Isaiah.
Look me in the eye.
Tell me you didn't
conspire to kill Ross.
Of course I didn't.
What in the world happened to
make you shoot at the President?
I don't know.
You gotta give me more
than "I don't know."
Is there anything you remember?
I got a haircut.
picked my suit up at the
cleaners and came to you.
We rode in the limo.
took our photo.
But my phone was on the fritz.
And then. we went
over to the East Room.
One moment I'm sittin' there.
the next I'm standin'
in that park.
I should have stayed
in my damn house.
minded my business.
No. this isn't on you.
Someone's behind all this.
Sam. the last thing I want
is for this to touch you.
[breathes shakily]
Besides...
Look. there ain't no
escapin' for me this time.
I'm gonna die in here.
No. you're not.
I'm gonna get you out.
- You wanna help me?
- [Sam] Of course.
Don't come back.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Guard.
[Ruth] Sergeant Payumo. get me
a copy of that conversation.
I wanna take another look.
Yes. ma'am.
And good work with Wilson.
Let me know if he
pays another visit.
Roger that.
[Sam] You get in?
[Joaquin] I think I committed
treason and espionage.
but I made it into the
White House's CCTV system.
What am I lookin' for?
[Sam] When Isaiah went
off in the White House.
it made me think of
a friend of mine.
He was being controlled
by trigger words.
Do you see any strangers
talkin' to Isaiah?
[Joaquin] No. well. we
got there. took a picture.
I AirDropped it to
him. but nothin' crazy.
Yeah. but he said his
phone was on the fritz.
Ah. Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Sam. I think I got something.
[Sam] What is it?
His phone is like
flashing at him.
Oh. shit. I got the same thing
happening to one of the other shooters.
What the hell?
Warden Cooper. Ross here.
The prisoner. he's secure?
I can confirm the
prisoner is in his cell.
Do we have eyes on the
bastard? Personally.
I'm looking at him
right now. sir.
Thank you. Cooper.
Thank you. Mr. President.
I keep goin' back to Mexico.
We were at the White House
because the buyer never showed.
Why hire SERPENT if you have
no intention on collecting?
Maybe they were expecting
Captain America to come.
What if the buyer wanted
Captain America to come?
And what if they wanted
us at the White House?
[Joaquin] But how
would the buyer predict
that we'd get the invite. or
that you would invite Isaiah?
[Sam] The buyer must
be watching us somehow.
Another thing.
Ruth Bat-Seraph. Ross's
security advisor.
find out what you can about her.
[Joaquin] Copy that.
I'll call you back later.
Target eliminated.
Stand by for proof of death.
[sirens wailing]
[tires screech]
Hmm.
[grunts]
[both grunting]
[groans]
[panting]
No way you came all the way from
Mexico just to blow up my car.
So you must have made
up with the buyer.
[grunts]
Get him on the phone.
Let me see if I
can resolve this.
"Resolve this"?
The buyer told me everything.
He mentioned that if you
survived the grenade.
there was a 77% chance
you'd try to talk me down.
Hmm.
Look at that.
[gunshot]
[Sam grunts]
[grunts]
[bullets clattering]
The buyer told me
a lot actually.
After he didn't show in Mexico.
he agreed to pay me
double to take you out.
What he doesn't know is that
I would kill you for free.
How often do you get a chance
to kill Captain America?
[sizzles]
You're desperate
without your gear.
[grunts]
[wheezing]
Nope.
Just a little meaner.
[wheezing]
- [grunts]
- [phone rings]
Hello.
[voice] Well done. Captain.
But you're not going to
like what's coming next.
[Sam] Who is this?
[phone beeps]
[Indian Prime Minister] How
can we trust you to lead
when you can't even keep
your own house in order?
We have the shooters in custody.
All I'm asking for is patience.
Patience?
From the Hulk Hunter?
That was a long time ago.
Well. Mr. President.
I was almost killed in
your home yesterday.
And today. you are still
locked in your bunker.
You are not in a position
to be asking for anything.
I agree.
We should continue this
conversation another time.
[Ross] Gentlemen. wait.
Please.
This treaty is too important
to let it fall apart now.
We made a promise to our people.
We made a promise to the world.
We must prevail.
We'll need Japan to proceed.
[French President] And Prime
Minister Ozaki's absence
speaks volumes.
I'll get Japan
back to the table.
Ozaki and I go back a long way.
He's running for re-election.
He needs to assert
leadership on this treaty.
All right. Mr. President.
we'll remain patient
while you try to
get Japan on board.
But if you don't.
we'll have to take measures
into our own hands.
I've gotta get out of here.
Sit down.
Sir. the sweep's not complete.
The longer I stay here.
the weaker I look.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[door opens]
The hell happened to you?
Sidewinder tracked me down.
[scoffs] Well. it looks like
he did a lot more than that.
He's in police custody now.
- Shit. you good?
- I will be.
Last call. trace it.
All right.
Yo. get this.
Ross' advisor. Ruth Bat-Seraph.
she was born in Israel and
trained in the Red Room.
She's ex-Widow.
That basically means stay
the hell out of her way.
Trust me.
Yep.
[Sam] Now. this is weird.
Isaiah had Ross
in his crosshairs.
Couldn't miss.
[Joaquin] I don't get it.
Why go through all that
trouble just to not kill Ross?
I don't know.
Oh. shit.
I think I located
Sidewinder's last caller.
It's in the middle of
nowhere. West Virginia.
It's just. like.
near some forest.
- [Joaquin typing]
- Database only shows one name.
Camp Echo One.
No satellite imagery.
Away from air traffic.
No infrastructure in the area.
- Do you think it's military?
- Yep.
It's a place they send
you and you never leave.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
Ross told me stay out of this.
Eh. he's just the President
of the United States.
[zipper closes]
You don't have to come with me.
Duh. I know. That's
what makes it so noble.
[chuckles]
Pack as much gear
as you can carry.
I don't know when we'll be back.
What. you mean like.
"right now" right now?
Yeah.
Oh. shit. Okay.
Well. it's a long-ass
drive to West Virginia.
so we're gonna need some snacks.
Why did I invite you?
What? Wait. wait. wait.
Wait up!
Ruth Bat-Seraph.
Isaiah Bradley's
in holding cell 14.
- The other shooters are in 15.
- Okay.
Do you need an escort?
- Think I'll be just fine.
- [door buzzes]
- Thanks.
- Yes. ma'am.
[door buzzes]
I'd like to speak to
them one at a time.
Can you... Excuse me?
Payumo. I'm talking to you. Hey.
- Stop! Drop your weapon!
- [gunshots]
[♪ unsettling music playing]
Payumo. what are you doing?
Drop it.
[gunshot]
[♪ The Fleetwoods "Mr.
Blue" playing over radio]
♪ Call me Mr. Blue ♪
♪ I'm Mr. Blue Wa-oo-wa-oo ♪
♪ When you say... ♪
[fitness coach on device] Increase
that cadence and resistance.
Or do whatever the hell you need
to do to get there. all right?
Just stay in your lane. Stay
in your lane. Here we go.
Out to third!
Eye on the prize. Eye
on the target. baby.
- [sighs] That's enough.
- Don't think about speed now.
Think about direction.
Think about intention.
If Dr. Eccles asks.
you tell her I did
the whole five miles.
That look. [panting]
We touch down in Tokyo at 0600.
You still think
this is a bad idea?
Sir. whoever orchestrated the attack on
the White House is still in the wild.
International travel brings
security risks we can't anticipate.
We barely got Congress
together on this thing.
If we lose our
international partners.
this treaty's toast.
I have to make this work.
Three miles and change.
I'll let Dr. Eccles know.
Five.
- Five.
Do we have eyes on Wilson?
He left the base a few hours
ago with Joaquin Torres.
They ditched their smartphones.
They're off-grid.
Well. I don't want a variable
out there that I can't control.
Get a team. pick him
up. bring him in.
- Yes. sir.
- Yeah.
[reporter on radio] Breaking
news out of Washington.
President Ross is
on his way to Japan
just a day after surviving
an assassination attempt...
Bet you used to play this
old-ass game all the time.
[exclaims] Damn
it. This is hard.
- [laughs]
- Right.
[reporter] The high-stakes
diplomatic visit...
How far are we
from Camp Echo One?
[reporter] ...over control
of Celestial Island.
We're about. like. an hour away.
[phone vibrates]
Sam. shit. They just
shot up Isaiah's prison.
Is he okay?
Yeah. Isaiah's good.
but the others.
they're dead.
Shit.
Should we go back?
No.
We keep going.
The buyer is pretty smart.
but we're not taking the bait.
Only way to help Isaiah is to
figure out who's behind this.
And whoever is behind it.
they do not want
us getting closer.
[phone vibrating]
Cooper.
What's happening?
[Cooper] Mr. President. as
a precautionary measure.
I have moved the prisoner to...
[gunshot]
President Ross. I miss
our little visits.
Tell me something.
Do you ever stop to ask yourself
who's playing the music?
It's you.
The White House. the
assassination attempt.
That's a way of putting it.
I helped you more
than anyone else.
Only to get what you want.
What do you want?
I wanted my life back. but
it's too late for that now.
You've gotta...
You gotta understand
my position.
- I...
- Oh. I do.
You let me rot in this prison.
And it was my curse
to watch your betrayal
written in probabilities.
I'm making my own choices now.
So many surprises left.
When I'm done. everyone
will know just who you are.
and Betty will
despise you even more.
Goodbye. Mr. President.
The hell is going on?
I'm putting you in solitary.
Yeah.
Nobody's gonna put me
in solitary ever again.
It's for your protection.
I'll tell you this one more
time for your protection.
I ain't goin' in
a box ever again.
I won't be able to
guarantee your safety.
Safety ain't all it's
cracked up to be.
You still think I had somethin'
to do with all of this?
I don't know.
[phone vibrates]
Mr. President.
[Ross] I need you to drop
whatever you're doin'.
Camp Echo One's
been compromised.
Yes. Mr. President.
This is it.
Camp Echo One.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Sam] Telescopes
must be a facade.
We gotta see what's underneath.
[Sam] We've got
cameras and guards.
Redwing. cut the fence
and go loop the feed.
Yeah. we got a 28-second
window to get past the guards.
We gotta do the door manually.
Three. two. one.
go.
[grunts]
15 seconds.
- I'm trying. man!
- [electricity crackles]
[Joaquin] Shit!
[Sam grunts]
[both grunting]
[doors clang]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[lights buzzing]
[Joaquin] There's no
prisoners in here.
[door clanking]
[Sam] Why is there a
lab in this prison?
What the hell is this place?
[Sam] What the hell?
[Ross] Ozaki-san.
I want to assure you
America remains committed
to sharing our adamantium
with the rest of the world.
I trust Japan shares
that commitment.
The world needs this treaty.
Diplomacy must be hard for you.
A man in a country
so used to taking whatever
he wants by force.
Excuse me?
How else to explain your
theft of our adamantium.
only to return it
to us in Washington.
What you're accusing
us of is baseless
and insulting.
So. the information my
intelligence team received
and verified
is incorrect?
[chuckles] Wh...
[Ross sighs]
I'm a fool.
I'm a fool to negotiate
with someone so naive
they don't realize
they're being played.
Naive?
If I'd stolen the sample.
why would I order Captain
America to retrieve it?
I suppose we'll
never know the truth.
Whatever game you're playing.
Japan wants no part in it.
Don't test us. Mr. President.
He's got optogenetic
data on a lot of people.
Don't make me look
up words. Joaquin.
I think he's figured out
a way to plant commands
into people's subconscious
using flashes of light.
This "Mr. Blue" song seems
to be some kind of trigger.
Mind control.
Yeah.
That explains Isaiah.
And that's more important.
Take risks.
Use those incredible
brains of yours.
[Sterns] Wasn't half
bad-looking. was I?
Samuel Sterns.
You know. It takes an
awful lot to surprise me.
[door buzzes]
There was an 89% chance
you'd turn around
if I put Isaiah Bradley at risk.
yet here you stand.
You're the buyer.
Indeed.
Hiring SERPENT was
a necessary step
to create a chain of
statistical certainties.
Maybe you're not as smart
as you think you are.
I am. actually.
My mind sees it all.
every probable outcome.
So you hire SERPENT to
steal the adamantium.
shoot up Ross'
summit announcing it
and now you're just
sitting here. waiting.
Why do you wanna kill Ross?
Why does everyone think
that I wanna kill Ross?
Is it because he imprisoned
me here without a trial
after an infusion of
gamma warped the structure
of my brain?
Damn.
Once Ross discovered
how useful I could be.
he kept me here for 16 years.
turning my mind to
solving his problems.
My solutions brought him the
highest office in the country.
If I wanted Ross
dead. he'd be dead.
Well. whatever you're doing.
you're hurting a lot of
people. including my friend.
So this is the last chance
I'm gonna give you to stop it.
Why are you protecting him?
Ross knows I'm responsible
for the White House.
yet he's still letting
Isaiah sit in prison for it.
You know he'll never change.
Let me finish my work.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
- [device whirring]
- [Sam grunting]
[groans]
Please don't be boring!
[grunts]
You think they'll stop us?
[Sterns] For long enough.
You're a fascinating problem.
But soon you'll
be off the board.
so you don't surprise me again.
This is messed up. man.
It's not even their choice.
I know. Just try and neutralize.
[all grunting]
[yelling]
[groans]
[Sam grunting]
[soldier groans]
[Joaquin] Punk-ass.
[grunts]
[door buzzes]
Stand down!
I'm taking them in.
I'll deal with these two.
[sighs] Okay.
[soldier groans]
What the hell are
you guys doing here?
Well. that's what I
should be asking you.
Where's Sterns?
If Sterns is in the wind.
we need to set a perimeter.
roadblocks. air support.
He can't have gone far.
Why are you helping us?
'Cause you were right. I
thought that was obvious.
- [FBI agent] Freeze!
- Oh. It's okay.
We have orders to take
Captain America into custody.
You already have one
Captain America in custody.
You want another?
You're under arrest for trespassing
on restricted government property.
Being right always go like this?
Most of the time.
I have the clearances.
It's been a long day.
She's ex-Widow.
Just zap the guy.
These orders come from
the President himself.
Get them out of here.
Then we'll just call him.
[♪ The Fleetwoods "Mr.
Blue" playing over radio]
Ruth. uncuff us now!
♪ I'm Mr. Blue Wa-oo-wa-oo ♪
♪ When you say... ♪
Oh. shit. shit. shit.
shit. Not again.
- Run!
- [Ruth] Go. go. go. Come on.
[grunts]
[Sam] Go!
[bullets ricochet]
[senior advisor] Mr. President.
Japan's claim seems to be true.
We're trying to determine
the point of the breach.
Sir. we have to tell
Ozaki's team something.
We've got to stop the bleeding.
I need some time alone.
We don't have much time. sir.
Ozaki just decided to advance
his navy on Celestial Island.
He intends to secure the
adamantium for himself.
[senior advisor] Jesus.
France and India are drawing
up occupation strategies...
Mr. President. I suggest that
we return to DC immediately.
- No. I disagree.
- Immediately.
We are going to lose our
opportunity with Ozaki.
We need to regroup and figure
out a different solution.
We can't do that.
No. absolutely not!
We need to ask for
another meeting. sir.
If we call on Ozaki now. and try
to reach out to him. we can...
We're not gonna
miss the argument.
We have to have another meeting!
- [advisors arguing]
- [yells]
[panting]
I want Carrier Strike Group
Five deployed immediately.
Tell 'em I'm on
my way there now.
Sir. are we seriously
talking about taking control
of Japan's adamantium?
I'm not going home empty-handed.
If only one country is
going to control adamantium.
it's going to be us.
Make the call!
Taylor!
[senior advisor] The
President has informed me
that we need to move Strike Group
Five to Celestial Island immediately.
I want to be en route to the
Indian Ocean within the hour.
Mr. President. this is
extremely dangerous.
If a war breaks out...
I was a wartime general.
Now I'm a wartime president.
Yes. sir. Mr. President.
What are we doing here?
You say Ross' orders was
to take us into custody
so I called in a favor.
Thanks for doing this.
No problem. Cap. Brass
never makes it down here.
Terminal's set up. ready to go.
You sure you can knock
out Sterns' mind control?
I should be able to run a program
that blocks the light signals
that Sterns has been sending
out to control people.
What if he's already
gotten someone?
That's a good point.
[♪ The Fleetwoods "Mr.
Blue" playing over speakers]
Are you crazy?
♪ I'm Mr. Blue Wa-oo-wa-oo ♪
♪ When you say you
love me Oh. Mr. Blue ♪
We're clear here. at least.
You have anybody that you trust
that can take a look at these
and tell me what's in 'em?
Sure. I got someone.
I'll get on it.
- Thanks. Our guy here?
- Through there.
Listen in.
[Sidewinder] I'm amazed
you're still standing.
Most men don't survive
an axe to the gut.
Kevlar weave. I presume?
Perks of the job.
You said you were gonna find
the man who wasted your time.
I wanna know what you learned.
Samuel Sterns.
Gruesome fella. don't you think?
I've seen worse.
Not without your Avengers.
[scoffs]
Full immunity and I'll talk.
[scoffs] You're crazy.
Who you kiddin'?
You're here because
you're all out of options.
You heard what he did
to those shooters.
A guy like Sterns doesn't
like loose ends alive.
[sighs]
Reduced sentence.
Allenwood. my own cell.
Lemme hear what you got first.
You know. it was my old
unit that found Sterns
in the wreckage of Harlem.
They said he'd been infected
with Bruce Banner's blood.
but it didn't give him strength.
What did it give him?
A mind capable of
impossible calculations.
Ross being Ross.
he saw an opportunity.
Instead of removing the
gamma from Sterns' blood.
he upped the dose.
Made Sterns his own
personal think tank.
creating technology and
weapons for the state.
- Holy shit.
- [chuckles]
Why did Sterns go along with it?
Camp Echo One was the stick.
I imagine a pardon
was the carrot.
Ross told Sterns he'd let him
go once he became president.
And yet. here we are.
So Sterns hired you to
steal Japan's adamantium
knowing it would divide
the two countries.
He paid us through
a CIA black fund.
That could kill the
treaty and start a war.
And Ross would be
blamed for the chaos.
How do you think a man
with Ross' temperament
will deal with being
caught in a trap?
If you break out of
Allenwood. I'll find you.
When I break out. Captain.
you won't walk away alive.
- Did you know?
- Of course not.
But Ross is not
that man anymore.
None of us have to be
defined by our past.
Cap. my guy needs 24
hours on the pills.
Okay. We need to get to DC and
tell Ross what Sterns is planning.
President Ross isn't in DC.
He's on the USS Milius.
They just moved into
the Indian Ocean.
Japan's warships are
also in proximity.
Shit. Suit up. We need to move.
[doorbell rings]
May I help you?
Hello. Admiral.
May I use your phone?
[family member] Hey.
honey. Who's at the door?
- [gunshots]
- [screams]
[Joaquin] Holy shit.
You ever see anything like this?
[Sam] No. I haven't.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Ruth] Let me do the talking
or he'll never listen.
I haven't seen Ross like
this since the army.
He better snap out of it.
Because whatever Sterns is
planning. it's happening soon.
[Ross] I want a fleet of
F-18s ready to catapult.
If they turn that
ship around. I want...
What's he doing here?
I told you not to
get involved. Wilson.
I brought him. sir.
[Ross] I want him outta here!
Sir. you asked me to
run this investigation.
- and the situation is...
- Don't bother with excuses.
You had a simple
job and you failed.
Mr. President.
we've uncovered intel
at Camp Echo One
that could put millions
of lives at risk.
Now. you and I both
know Isaiah's innocent.
I'm happy to have this
conversation in public.
if you like.
[Jackal] This is crazy.
Japan's supposed to be our...
- [radio feedback squeals]
- [Whiskey] Jackal?
Jackal. do you copy?
[♪ The Fleetwoods "Mr.
Blue" playing over radio]
♪ I'm Mr. Blue ♪
Make it quick. Wilson.
I've got Japan's fleet on my ass
trying to make it to
that island before we do.
That's exactly what he wants.
Sterns has been pulling
the strings on everything.
SERPENT's theft
of the adamantium.
the attack on the White House.
The CIA leak to Japan.
He's pitting you and
Japan against each other
to ensure that this
moment happens.
How the hell did he do
all that from prison?
Mind control. He
created a technology
that allowed him to control the
minds of anyone he targeted.
Including maybe you. sir.
[♪ tense music playing]
Have you been feelin'
like yourself lately?
Of course I have.
But he has your data. sir. Why?
I don't know.
If he can control minds.
surely he can hack files.
The logs show that you visited
Camp Echo One numerous times.
To ensure a high-value
prisoner was secure.
Yeah. but the scans. the EKG. the
blood work was all taken there. sir.
This is ridiculous.
Mr. President.
answer the question.
I don't have to answer you!
Why visit a Black Site.
- in the middle of nowhere...
- Wilson. stop!
I order you to stop!
- ...to conduct these tests?
- I order you to stop!
- Why?
- Because I was dying.
goddamn it!
[♪ tense music continues]
Because my heart was failing!
No one could figure
it out until he did.
These things have kept me alive.
And in return. I gave him hope
that he might get his life back.
He got a lab to do the work.
I even tried to get
him moved but...
But you couldn't risk
losing the pills.
After your friend the
Hulk and the Abomination
destroyed Harlem. someone
had to take the fall.
Sterns was just...
collateral damage.
I have dedicated my entire life
to serving this country.
The one person that matters...
doesn't seem to understand.
Betty never forgave me for
sending the army after Banner.
I had to survive...
[♪ sentimental music playing]
...so that my daughter knew that
there was more to her father.
That I'm the same man
that used to take her
to see the cherry blossoms.
She still can. sir.
I know what it's like...
to feel you have
somethin' to prove.
Everyone only seeing one thing.
But when showing
there's more to you.
it's not about when
times are easy.
It's about moments like this.
Now. we're here because
Sterns wants revenge
and doesn't care if
he incites a war.
We're playing right
into his hand.
Mr. President. two of our F-18s
just fired on the Japanese fleet.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[male commander] Keep
hailing those pilots.
[male specialist] Damage
to Japanese fleet minimal.
[male commander] Ready
air defense systems.
[Ross] What the hell
are those pilots doing?
- Call them back in.
- [male commander] We tried. sir.
Jackal and Whiskey
won't respond.
We gotta get our
birds in the air.
You have two ready
to fly now. sir.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
Go.
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[Joaquin] Sterns got to our pilots
before I shut down the system.
[Captain America] We need to
get the Japanese out of the air.
Stay close and don't
get yourself killed.
[Joaquin] No dying. copy that.
Return to your fleet.
[in Japanese] Yamamoto.
we've got company.
[Captain America. in Japanese]
There's been a mistake.
We're not your enemy.
- [gunfire]
- [grunts]
[Captain America] Jackal's headed
towards the Japanese fleet.
Shit! He just fired on them.
Mr. President. do not
send more fighters up.
We need Japan to see we're
trying to deescalate.
[in Japanese] Command. permission
to return fire on the Americans?
[in Japanese]
Permission granted.
[male specialist] Sir. we have
six Japanese missiles inbound.
Launch intercept missiles.
[Joaquin] Damn. two got through.
[Captain America] Take
the one on the right.
Redwing. a little help.
Sir. you need to convince
Japan to ground their planes.
[Ozaki] This is what we
expected from a Ross presidency.
Mr. Prime Minister. two of
our pilots have gone rogue.
Call off your planes.
We're being manipulated.
[Ozaki] Certainly.
By you.
Hiding your assassins
behind Captain America.
He's trying to bring
them down now. sir.
If those pilots are not
taking orders from you.
then who gives them
their commands?
That's what I thought.
[line disconnects]
[male commander] Mr. President?
[groans]
[Sterns through earpiece] Ah.
now we're getting somewhere.
That fire in the
belly. The rage.
Why don't you just let it out?
Are you all right. sir?
[Ross breathes heavily]
[stammering] I
just need a moment.
[♪ tense music playing]
Joaquin. Whiskey's
coming at you.
[Joaquin] Copy that.
Sam. once we're done. you
gotta teach me your moves!
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[alarm system]
Altitude. Altitude.
Altitude.
[Joaquin] Whiskey's
away. Send rescue.
[male specialist]
Roger. sending rescue.
You have two Japanese fighters
coming up on your tail.
[Joaquin] Why the hell
are they still chasing us?
We're trying to help them.
[Captain America] Because
Ross won't tell them
who's really behind this.
[Sterns] All that
hatred you try to hide.
all the ugliness. it's
still there. Ross.
smoldering behind the eyes.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Captain America] Joaquin.
I'm goin' after Jackal.
[Joaquin] Roger that.
I'll keep these guys busy.
What have you done
to me. you bastard?
[Sterns] What we agreed
on. Maybe a hair more.
[Ross] You poisoned me!
[Sterns] Stop taking
the pills then.
But we both know you won't.
Give me what I want.
Stop fighting it.
No!
[♪ dramatic music continues]
[Joaquin] Sam. Jackal just
fired his last missiles!
I got one. Going
after the another.
- Back off! I'll get it!
- [Joaquin] No. no! I got it.
- Back off!
- I got it.
[yells]
Joaquin!
Joaquin's down! I'm
goin' after him.
We'll send search and rescue.
You have to stop Jackal.
Damn it!
I'm putting an end to this now.
[Sterns] Give in to your rage.
I'm taking your
legacy as we speak.
Come on. Ross.
You're almost there.
You can rip their fleet
apart with your bare hands.
and kill Captain America.
[rapid beeping]
Oh. shit.
[grunts]
[Sterns] Let the
monster inside you out.
[grunting]
[alarm system] Altitude.
altitude. altitude.
Altitude. altitude. altitude.
[Sterns] Unleash your anger.
Unleash your hatred.
[Captain America]
Redwing. stabilize!
[Sterns] Nothing
can stop you. Ross.
You can crush them all.
[♪ triumphant music playing]
[Leila] Mr. President?
Sir. Are you okay?
Captain America neutralized
the rogue pilots.
Japan's recalling their planes.
[Ross pants]
Get Ozaki back on the line.
We can fix this.
[hyperventilating]
[in Japanese] Command. Captain
America saved our fleet.
American pilots neutralized.
[♪ tense music playing]
Where's Joaquin?
Med-evac just got to him.
[Captain America] Thank God.
[reporter] A crisis
was narrowly avoided
when a brief dogfight broke out
between Japanese and US military forces
over Celestial Island.
US Air Force Captain Joaquin Torres
was shot down during the skirmish.
and is now in surgery at
Walter Reed National
Military Medical Center.
His condition is critical.
- [surgeon 1] Give me that clamp.
- [surgeon 2] Gonna need to pack this!
- [surgeon 1] The pressure's stable.
- [surgeon 2] Suction!
I can't see anything.
More suction.
Retractors.
[footsteps approaching]
It's a private room.
Go away.
I missed you. too.
I hate to admit it.
I'm glad you're here.
[sighs]
You looked good out there
on that six o'clock.
But then I saw this.
The doctors had to
restart his heart.
They don't know if...
This isn't your fault.
It makes me think of Steve.
How many alien invasions
did he stop again?
Two.
[scoffs]
Wow.
What made me think
I could follow that?
I should've took the serum.
Like Steve. like you.
Why?
Because this is all startin'
to seem much bigger than me.
Ross. he asked me to
restart the Avengers. Buck.
But Joaquin's in here.
Isaiah's in prison.
and Sterns...
I had him. I had Sterns
right in my hands.
And he got away.
He damn near pushed us
to the brink of war.
because I wasn't...
Say what you need to say.
Steve made a mistake.
No. he didn't.
He gave you that shield
not because you're
the strongest.
but because you're you.
You think if you had that serum
you'd be able to protect all
the people you care about.
Steve had it. and he couldn't.
You're a human being. and
you're doing your best.
Steve gave people
something to believe in.
But you...
you give 'em something
to aspire to.
Did your speechwriters
help you with that?
They did. yeah. The
ending. a little bit.
Well. did you like it?
No. no. it was
good. Solid B-plus.
- Emotional.
- Yeah. very. I felt it.
But just enough.
Yeah.
Listen. I gotta catch a plane.
I have a campaign
fundraiser. It's so stupid.
It's gonna be all right. man.
Thanks. Buck.
I love you. buddy.
- Was that...
- Yep.
Future Congressman
James Buchanan Barnes.
He's taller in real
life. nice smile too.
good amount of
teeth. great posture.
He's 110 years old.
I can work with that.
[reporter on TV] While the investigation
into the White House assassination attempt
and the shocking shooting at
Joint Base Anacostia-Bolling
is still under way.
Isaiah Bradley is set to go
before a military judge tomorrow.
I need some air.
It's a stunning fall
from grace for a man
brought out from the
shadows by Captain America.
Just two years after being
exonerated for unjust charges.
Bradley now finds himself
held in solitary confinement
and facing a possible
death sentence.
[phone rings]
[instructor] Okay.
reset. Let's go again.
Talk to me.
[scientist] Dunphy. you
check out my report?
All right. what am I looking at?
Those pills you gave me. they're
loaded with gamma radiation.
engineered to be
absorbed into the blood.
Where the hell
did you get these?
Shit. I gotta make a call.
[distorted pulsing sound]
[groans]
This sound is currently
affecting your equilibrium.
When I turn this dial.
it will disrupt your heartbeat.
I take no pleasure
in your death.
but I can't have you
calling the Captain.
[panting] Who are you?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm the hero.
[distorted pulsing intensifies]
[muffled scream]
[♪ unsettling music playing]
[door opens]
[Leila] Sir.
- Agent Taylor.
- [door closes]
Just wanted to let you know that
every guest has been screened.
and we also did three
sweeps of the Rose Garden.
Thank you.
- See you out there.
- Yes. sir.
[door closes]
[dial tone]
- [Betty] Hello?
- [stammers]
Hello. Hi.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
I... how are you?
I'm sorry. I should have called
after the attack at the White House.
Are you okay?
Oh...
I'm fine.
It's really good
to hear your voice.
I didn't think you'd answer.
Betty. I... I know I've
made a lot of mistakes.
But I'm trying to change.
to be a better person.
Um...
Maybe we could take
a... a walk sometime?
See the cherry blossoms.
like the old days.
Yeah. That could be nice.
Okay. I love you.
Bye. Dad.
[reporters chattering]
Please.
Good afternoon. everyone.
When I took office.
I promised we would create
a true. lasting peace.
Today. we begin to
realize that promise.
[Sterns] Captain America...
would you do me the kindness
of counseling a bitter man
at the end of his rope?
That's what you do. isn't it?
Guess we have five minutes until
the MPs drag your ass outta here.
You ruined my grand finale
on the Indian Ocean.
So now I'm forced to turn
myself in to get what I want.
Well. if you're
waitin' for an apology.
we'll be here awhile.
I'm waiting for you to realize
that we both want
the same thing.
for the world to see
Ross as he truly is.
I'm proud to say our treaty
will finally be signed.
I'll take a couple questions.
Sir. what do you say to reports
that relations with Japan broke down
over your handling of the White
House assassination attempt?
Despite fabrications
that some have used
to turn us against each other.
our bonds have proved strong.
You kept Ross alive for years.
Didn't kill him when you had
the chance at the White House.
The way I see it.
the Indian Ocean wasn't
about starting a war.
You wanted to
destroy his legacy.
Yes.
But you haven't figured out how.
The pills.
I got somebody on that. too.
Not anymore. you don't.
Is it true hostilities
in the Indian Ocean
occurred because the
Japanese discovered
it was. in fact. your government
who paid for the SERPENT mercenary
group to steal their adamantium?
We did not pay them.
Ross turned me into a monster.
It's only right that I
do the same thing to him.
Why aren't you smiling?
- On the ground!
- Hold it!
You ever use that
big brain of yours
to consider that maybe
you're wrong about Ross?
Wanna bet?
[Sam] Yeah.
- Where are you going?
- To stop this.
Get on the ground. now.
You have the right
to remain silent...
Captain America!
If I'm right about Ross.
you're going to die.
You're going to die!
Mr. President. Dr. Samuel
Sterns just turned himself in.
He claims you
promised him a pardon
if he worked on secret
government projects for you.
- That is a lie.
- [reporters murmuring]
[Sterns through speaker] President
Ross. I miss our little visits.
[Ross through speaker]
What do you want?
[Sterns] I wanted my life back.
but it's too late for that now.
Sir...
[Ross] I helped you
more than anyone.
Well. let me explain.
They have to know.
[Ross] You gotta
understand my position.
[Sterns] Oh. I do. You
let me rot in this prison.
Leave me alone!
- Leave me! Let me go!
- [Leila] Sir! Sir!
I cannot let you.
- You can't let me? Let me?
- I cannot...
[Sterns] Everyone will
know just who you are.
And Betty will
despise you even more.
Sir. please.
[shouting]
[agent] Sir.
[Ross groaning]
Oh. my God.
[Ross growling]
[reporters clamoring]
[roars]
Since when were they red?
[♪ ominous music playing]
President Ross?
[growls. grunts]
Agent Taylor. do we fire?
[roars]
[reporters scream]
This is what Sterns wanted.
Jesus.
Sam. I gotta get these
people outta here.
[Captain America]
Set a perimeter
- around the White House.
- [roars]
[Captain America grunts]
[gunfire]
[Captain America] No.
Fall back. Fall back!
Get down!
[Ruth] Sam. drones incoming.
[roars]
Ruth. I need you to
clear Hains Point.
I'll lure Ross there.
[Ruth] Sam. are you
crazy? He'll kill you.
[Captain America] Do it!
[Ross grunting]
You can still fight this. Ross.
Do you see where you are?
You remember this place?
You used to come
here with Betty.
[roars]
That didn't work.
Okay.
You want me?
Come and get me!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[grunts. groans]
[boosters pulsing]
[grunting]
[boosters fade]
[straining]
[Ruth] Sam? Sam.
can you hear me?
[Leila] Sam. are you okay?
Please tell me I knocked
that son of a bitch out.
[sirens wailing]
[crash]
Shit.
Backup's five minutes away.
[straining] No. tell them wait.
What?
[♪ ominous music playing]
Should've taken that serum.
Bucky is full of shit.
[Ross growls]
I'm gonna lose that bet.
Ross.
We both know you can take
me out with one punch.
but I don't think
you wanna do that.
I know you've done
some terrible things.
Now. I might be crazy...
but I think you're
trying to change.
Now's the time to
prove it to the world.
Prove it to Betty.
[♪ sentimental music playing]
The army is transferring
Sterns to a secure facility.
We should get you
to the hospital.
There's somewhere
we gotta go first.
[♪ uplifting music playing]
That's three. old man.
I told you I'd get you out.
Took you so long?
[chuckles]
Thank you. Sam.
I got you.
I have a few broken bones. so...
[laughs]
Come on. Mr. Bradley.
We got a little
paperwork to fill out.
and then you're free to go.
[reporter] Worldwide
talks continue
in the arms race for the
newly discovered element.
as we enter the brave
new world of adamantium.
Back in our nation's
capital. ground was broken
on the restoration
of the White House.
marking a significant step
towards normalcy for the country.
Right this way.
Mr. President. How're your digs?
Intentionally uncomfortable.
I heard the food hasn't
got any better either.
- You heard right.
- [chuckles]
Bradley got out?
Yes. sir.
That's good.
Mr. President. about
your blood work.
It seems Sterns raised
the level of gamma
in those pills over time.
It built up in your
body over the years.
That led to your...
Led to my little tantrum.
Which is why I
have to be in here.
Good solid walls. these.
Yeah.
But I have to say.
it wasn't nothin' to see you take
full responsibility for your actions.
Give up your office.
Accept your sentence.
I had to let the
country move on.
Japan decided to uphold
the treaty. by the way.
Us too.
The Ozaki-Ross Accords.
You did it.
Sam. why are you here?
[Sam] Sir?
We were on different sides of
this thing every step of the way.
Look. if we can't see
the good in each other.
we've already lost the fight.
Besides. I wanted to make
sure an old soldier was okay.
I'd love to stay. but looks
like you have another visitor.
Hi. Dad.
I guess I have to give you
a raincheck on that walk.
It's all right.
We could just sit and
talk for a little while.
I'd like that.
Me too.
How's the kid doin' today?
He's still a little out
of it but doin' better.
I'm gonna let you two catch up.
Hey. where you headed?
Back to Baltimore?
No.
I got Ruth and me tickets for
tonight's game. courtside.
It's the least I could
do for gettin' me out.
I'm happy you found a friend as
grumpy as you are to go to games with.
Say it again.
[Sam stammers]
[chuckling] I'm
playing. Got you.
[EKG machine beeping]
The Falcon awakens.
Couldn't let you
have all the fun.
I'm sorry I screwed up.
Screwed up? Get out of here.
I did.
You never messed up like I have.
You never got shot
out of the sky
and nosedived into
the Indian Ocean.
You're always on point.
[scoffs]
Yeah.
Because if I'm not on point...
I feel like I let down
everyone else who was fightin'
for a seat at that table.
That's pressure. man.
It weighs on you.
Makes you wonder if
you'll ever just be...
enough.
Where I grew up.
I only ever got to
see heroes online.
Or on TV.
It always felt so far away.
And I kept thinkin' maybe
if I get out of Miami.
you know. maybe one
day I could be...
Don't say Ant-Man.
[laughs]
- No. man.
- [chuckles]
I wanted to be you.
Well...
[Joaquin] Sam Wilson.
Because that guy? That
guy won't ever give up.
That pressure. that
responsibility you talk about?
I want that too. man.
You know it's all
about timin'. right?
Control your spin. then hit
your thruster before you kick.
- No.
- [gasps] Yeah.
- No. That's...
- [laughs]
That's it.
I should get shot out
of the sky more often.
Yeah. you will.
- Okay. [chuckles]
- [laughs]
You know. you're gonna
come back from this.
I know.
And when that time comes.
make sure the suit's ready.
'cause Ross was right
about one thing.
The world needs the Avengers.
- For real?
- Yeah.
Hell. yeah. [chuckles]
I wasn't thinking about it before.
but now that you bring it up...
Oh. boy.
...since the wings are damaged.
I was thinking. I'm
like. what could make...
No.
You didn't hear
- what I was gonna ask you.
- No. Whatever you ask. nope.
I'm just saying. maybe you have.
like. the Wakandans on speed dial
and could get me some...
A hookup on an
upgrade on the wings.
You're gonna ask the
Wakandans for a hookup?
Yeah.
That is the most Miami
thing in the world.
Are you kidding? They
gonna hook me up. man. Yo.
[♪ uplifting hip hop.
Kendrick Lamar "i" playing]
[♪ tense music playing]
Told you you were
gonna lose that bet.
You wanna know what's funny?
I'm not in the mood
for your jokes.
You killed a lot of good men
trying to get your revenge.
Trust me. we don't share
the same sense of humor.
We share the same
world. don't we?
This world you
would die to save?
It's coming.
I've seen it in
the probabilities.
seen it plain as day.
All you heroes
protecting this world...
do you think you're
the only ones?
Do you think this
is the only world?
We'll see what happens
when you have to protect
this place from the others.
[♪ dramatic music
crescendos. fades]